A Guide to the Carol Barton Papers, 1973-2015: SC 0274
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Carol Barton Papers,
1973-2015
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Barton, Carol June, 1954-
SC 0274
6.67 cubic feet; 18 boxes, 1 flat file
The Carol Barton Papers, 1973-2015, contain printed materials, letters, brochures, and primary materials as well as items that document professional endeavors, artistic processes, and personal items of book artist, paper engineer, teacher, and curator, Carol Barton.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open to research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Carol Barton on March 23, 2017. Manuscript material was also received as part of a 2015 acquisition of Carol Barton's personal and teaching collection of pop-up and artists' books. That material was incorporated into this collection.
Appraisal Note
In addition to analog manuscript material, Carol Barton transferred three digital audio files of podcasts on which she had been a guest including Santa Fe Radio Café (March 17, 2008), Book Artists and Poets (July 15, 2009), and Beyond the Page: Carol Barton's Art and Influence: a podcast with Carol Barton and the Nashville Public Library. These files were not retained and not incorporated into the collection.
Bio/Historical Note
Carol Barton, born on June 3, 1954 in St. Louis, Missouri, is an accomplished book artist, paper engineer, educator, and curator who has exhibited internationally (The Smithsonian Institution, Library of Congress, Museum of Modern Art, Victoria and Albert Museum in London) and has curated shows such as Books & Bookends: Science and the Artist's Book (Smithsonian). Inspired by reading, historical references, functional objects, architecture, and other artists' book, Barton is best known for her interactive workbooks, The Pocket Paper Engineer. Five Luminous Towers: Books to Read in the Dark, which was awarded the Bogliasco Fellowship in 2000, Vision Shifts, Instructions for Assembly, and Tunnel Map are other major works. A graduate of Washington University School of Fine Arts (1976), Barton has served as a faculty member at the University of the Arts in Philadelphia and the Corcoran College of Art & Design and has taught at the elementary and high school level. In 1977, Barton moved to Washington D.C. to work for the Glen Echo Park Arts Center. Through her time there and through the promotion of artists' books by local art group, The Writer's Center, Barton learned pre-press skills that allowed her to print her own work. She was later offered a small grant to produce her own artists' books. Having grown up as the daughter of a diesel engine mechanic, Barton's love for structural and mechanical elements was formed as she grew up building and playing with construction games and tinker toys. Movable books, better known as pop-ups, were not a part of her childhood. However, after the success of her first book, Beyond the Page (1981), Barton began a two year study of pop-up and movable books at the Dibner Rare Book Library and the Library of Congress to find early examples of dimensional and movable books. This research most likely resulted in her 1988 publication of her tunnel book, Everyday Road Signs.
In 1992, Barton served as James Madison University's first Wampler Visiting Professor of Fine Art and has intermittently served as a visiting artist and professor. JMU Libraries acquired Barton's collection of artists' and movable books in 2015, and in March 2017 Barton returned to JMU as a guest lecturer for the Carrier Library Special Collections Speaker Series. The event was marked with Barton discussing her career and work; as well as, facilitating a book arts workshop with the Intermediate book arts students, and ending with a public lecture and reception in the Duke Hall Gallery Court.
Scope and Content
The Carol Barton Papers, 1973-2015, include catalogues, letters, printed materials, journals, special publications, interviews, artist statements, artist projects, and project plans throughout the donor's career. The collection includes teaching tools, personal research, practice and planning, and commemoration of events in which Barton participated.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series:
Series 1: Printed Materials, 1973-2015
Series 2: Projects and Research, 1975-2012
Series 3 Ephemera and Personal Papers, 1979-2013
The collection is arranged according to material type and function. All series are arranged chronologically. All folders and boxes are arranged chronologically. Location irregularities are documented in the container list. Exceptions to this arrangement were made in order to group like materials together. In the 'Exhibition Catalogs, 1993 (folder 2 of 2)', a digital floppy disk of Barton's exhibition, Miliseconds to Milennia: The Art of Time, Hand Workshop, has been placed in this folder. The floppy disk is a copy of an old Word Perfect file.
Related Material
Carol Barton's personal and teaching collection of movable books and artists' books, which were acquired separately from her papers, are cataloged individually and are housed in the James Madison University's Special Collections.
Separated Material
Numerous books, artists' books, toys, and publications were pulled from the collection, cataloged individually, and added to Special Collections' rare book holdings. Ker-Bloom!, a series of art publications, were also separated and cataloged.
Select items were discarded from the collection due to preservation concerns, deterioration, duplicates, or preexisting damage.
Bibliography
Grace Barth, Liana Bayne, and Caroline Hamby. "History of Pop-up and Movable Books, About This Exhibit." Carol Barton Collection, JMU Special Collections. Accessed September, 2018, https://omeka.lib.jmu.edu/specialcollections/exhibits/show/carol-barton/about.
Barton, Carol. "Popular Kinetics Press." Accessed September, 2018. https://www.popularkinetics.com/.
National Museum of Women. "About the Artist, Carol Barton". Accessed September 2018. https://nmwa.org/explore/artist-profiles/carol-june-barton.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Barton, Carol June, 1954-; Artists' books; Pop-up books; Toy and movable books; Paper work; Cut-out craft
Genre and Form Terms:
Manuscripts (documents); Letters (correspondence); exhibition catalogs; Printed Ephemera; Promotional materials; Newspaper clippings; Prototypes (object genre); Movable books
- Series 1: Printed Materials, 1973-2015
  Scope and Content
  Series 1: Printed Materials, 1973-2015, comprises various exhibition catalogs, book catalogs, gallery cards, articles, journals, interviews, artist statements and pamphlets for workshops that Barton taught.
  Throughout her career, Carol Barton has been celebrated in numerous articles and journals: The Bone Folder (2000 & 2009), "Surface: New Form/New Function" (review by Carol Barton), The Smithsonian Associates (August 2001), "Ancient Sichuan's Artistic Treasures", Valley Art Association Newsletter (May-June 1999), and The Washington Print Club Quarterly (Barton is featured on pages 6-9) are examples included within the Carol Barton Papers.
  Barton has also been referenced in newspaper articles, online publications, and reviews such as The Washington Times, New York Times, Smithsonian Associates, and Boston Globe.
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1973-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition catalogs (folder 1 of 2), 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Exhibition catalogs (folder 2 of 2), 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition catalogs (folder 1 of 3), 1999 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Exhibition catalogs (folder 2 of 3), 1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition catalogs (folder 3 of 3), 1999 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 2004-2005 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 2014-2015 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Exhibition catalogs, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Book catalogs, 1982-1997 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Book catalogs, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Book catalogs, 1996-2000 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Book catalogs, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Book catalogs, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Book catalogs, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Book catalogs (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Book catalogs (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Promotional materials, 1992-2010 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Promotional materials (folder 1 of 5), undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Promotional materials (folder 2 of 5), undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Promotional materials (folder 3 of 5), undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Promotional materials (folder 4 of 5), undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Promotional materials (folder 5 of 5), undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper articles, online publications, and reviews, 1981-2012 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper and article reviews, Cooper-Hewitt, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Artist statements, 1988-2014 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "Playful Readings: A History of Children's Movable Books" article reviews, 1990-1995 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1992-2013 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Teaching workshop publications, 1996-2003 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Workbook Volume 1-3 Extra Card Set, 2005-2012 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 1 Extra Card Set, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Interviews, 2008-2010 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Series 2: Projects and Research, 1975-2012
  Series 2: Projects and Research, 1975-2012, contains Barton's professional projects, project planning, and items used for project research. Instructions for Assembly (1993) contains process plans, mock-ups, instructions, patents used for inspiration, and process materials. Vision Shifts (1998) contains process plans, mock-ups, large scale prints, and photographs. Five Luminous Towers: A Book to Read in the Dark (2001) includes sample pieces, planning materials, and templates for The Lookout. As well, the book La Torre e le Carceri di Palazzo Ducale served as direct inspiration for Five Luminous Towers: A Book to Read in the Dark. Barton's first book, Beyond the Page (1981), contains hand cut master sheets. Everyday Road Signs (1988) contains a prototype of the book's binding, planning for the first five pages of Separations, sample material for page six, negatives, text copy for the opening page, and print prototypes for a page. Loom (1989) contains design prototypes, steel plates, and text copy and print. Tunnel Map (1988) contains planning for Map #1 Europe/Africa/Asia in a blue separation, page design plans, book cover design plans, and the first set of unused map film originals. Page design plans for Tunnel Map include: page 2 for North/South America, page 3 for Africa/Europe, page 4 for North/South America, page 5 for North/South America and Africa/Europe, and page 6 for Africa/Europe and North/South America.
  Researchers should note that dates for Carol Barton's plans/prototypes are approximate and based on the year the specific project was published.
  Prototypes of Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 3 are housed with a related promotional poster. The poster is for "a visiting artist lecture sponsored by the MFA Book Arts/Printmaking Program at the University of the Arts (Philadelphia)."
  Barton has also been referenced in promotional materials regarding her work in: Visual Icons, Small Works: The Gallery at Studio B, Art on the Page: A Selection of Artists' Books, Orihon & More: Books By Artists, Under Cover: Book Arts, Beyond Reading, [Book] Art: Handmade Books, Book For[u]ms, The Pocket Paper Engineer, Washington University Libraries Special Collections, and Mining the Lloyd.
  - Project research, 1975-2006 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Inspirational research, 1975-2014 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Beyond the Page, 1981 (Box OV 1, Folder 4a)
  - Beyond the Page and Loom project plans, and unplated aluminum lithograph, 1981, 1989 (Box OV 1, Folder 4a)
  - Everyday Road Signs cover (folder 1 of 10), 1988 (Box OV 1, Folder 1a)
  - Everyday Road Signs page 1 (folder 2 of 10), 1988 (Box OV 1, Folder 1a)
  - Everyday Road Signs page 2 separations (folder 3 of 10), 1988 (Box OV 1, Folder 1a)
  - Everyday Road Signs page 3 separations (folder 4 of 10), 1988 (Box OV 1, Folder 1a)
  - Everyday Road Signs page 4 separations (folder 5 of 10), 1988 (Box OV 1, Folder 1a)
  - Everyday Road Signs page 6 separations (folder 6 of 10), 1988 (Box OV 1, Folder 1a)
  - Everyday Road Signs binding separations (folder 7 of 10), 1988 (Box OV 1, Folder 1a)
  - Everyday Road Signs book cover (folder 8 of 10), 1988 (Box OV 1, Folder 1a)
  - Everyday Road Signs negatives (folder 9 of 10), 1988 (Box OV 1, Folder 1a)
  - Tunnel Map cover plans (folder 10 of 10), 1988 (Box OV 1, Folder 1a)
  - Tunnel Map map films, designs for pages 2-6, 1988 (Box OV 1, Folder 3a)
  - Loom, 1989 (Box OV 1, Folder 4a)
  - Loom unplated aluminum lithographs, 1989 (Box OV 1, Folder 4a)
  - Artists' Books Women's Studio Workshop, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Instructions for Assembly plans, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - A Pop-up Workbook: How to Make Your Own prototype, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Paper Mechanics: A History of Pop-up & Movable Books prototype, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Instructions for Assembly book instructions, 1993 (Box OV 1, Folder 2a)
  - Inspiration, A Step-by-Step Guide, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Science and the Artist's Book, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Vision Shifts plans, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Vision Shifts unplated aluminum lithographs, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Vision Shifts photographic research, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Vision Shifts plans (folder 1 of 3), 1998 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Vision Shifts plans (folder 2 of 3), 1998 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Vision Shifts plans (folder 3 of 3), 1998 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Vision Shifts promotional materials, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Five Luminous Towers: A Book to Read in the Dark process/project plans, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Five Luminous Towers: A Book to Read in the Dark sample pieces, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Five Luminous Towers: A Book to Read in the Dark templates for The Lookout, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Five Luminous Towers: A Book to Read in the Dark project plans, 2001 (Box OV 1, Folder 5a)
  - Five Luminous Towers: A Book to Read in the Dark oversized aluminum plate and transparency paper, 2001 (Mapcase 3, Drawer 10, Folder 1)
  - Promotional information, 2001-2004 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 1 plans (folder 1 of 2), 2005 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 1 plans (folder 2 of 2), 2005 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 1 cover prototype, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 1 book prototypes (folder 1 of 10), 2005 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 1 book prototypes (folder 2 of 10), 2005 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 1 book prototypes (folder 3 of 10), 2005 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 1 book prototypes (folder 4 of 10), 2005 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 1 book prototypes (folder 5 of 10), 2005 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 1 book prototypes (folder 5 of 10), 2005 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 1 book prototypes (folder 7 of 10), 2005 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 1 book prototypes (folder 8 of 10), 2005 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 1 book prototypes (folder 9 of 10), 2005 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 1 book prototypes (folder 10 of 10), 2005 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - It's Only a Paper Moon, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - A Pop-Up Inauguration Celebration! plans and prototype, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 cover prototype, 2008 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 project plans and prototypes (folder 1 of 15), 2008 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 project plans and prototypes (folder 2 of 15), 2008 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 project plans and prototypes (folder 3 of 15), 2008 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 project plans and prototypes (folder 4 of 15), 2008 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 project plans and prototypes (folder 5 of 15), 2008 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 project plans and prototypes (folder 6 of 15), 2008 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 project plans and prototypes (folder 7 of 15), 2008 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 project plans and prototypes (folder 8 of 15), 2008 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 project plans and prototypes (folder 9 of 15), 2008 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 project plans and prototypes (folder 10 of 15), 2008 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 project plans and prototypes (folder 11 of 15), 2008 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 project plans and prototypes (folder 12 of 15), 2008 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 project plans and prototypes (folder 13 of 15), 2008 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 project plans and prototypes (folder 14 of 15), 2008 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 project plans and prototypes (folder 15 of 15), 2008 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 and 3 book prototypes, 2008, 2012 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 and 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 1 of 13), 2008, 2012 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 and 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 2 of 13), 2008, 2012 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 and 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 3 of 13), 2008, 2012 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 and 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 3 of 13), 2008, 2012 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 and 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 5 of 13), 2008, 2012 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 and 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 6 of 13), 2008, 2012 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 and 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 7 of 13), 2008, 2012 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 and 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 8 of 13), 2008, 2012 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 and 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 9 of 13), 2008, 2012 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 and 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 10 of 13), 2008, 2012 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 and 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 11 of 13), 2008, 2012 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 and 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 12 of 13), 2008, 2012 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 2 and 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 13 of 13), 2008, 2012 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - A Pop-Up Inauguration Celebration! newspaper version, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 3 pop-up design prototypes (folder 1 of 5), 2012 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 3 pop-up design prototypes (folder 2 of 5), 2012 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 3 pop-up design prototypes (folder 3 of 5), 2012 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 3 pop-up design prototypes (folder 4 of 5), 2012 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 3 pop-up design prototypes (folder 5 of 5), 2012 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 3 cover prototype, 2012 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 3 instruction diagrams, chapters 1-5, 2012 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 1 of 10), 2012 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 2 of 10), 2012 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 3 of 10), 2012 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 4 of 10), 2012 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 5 of 10), 2012 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 6 of 10), 2012 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 7 of 10), 2012 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 8 of 10), 2012 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 9 of 10), 2012 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 3 project plans and prototypes (folder 10 of 10), 2012 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Torii Gate and teahouse cards, 2012 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer Volume 3 oversized prototypes, 2012 (Box OV 1)
  - Pop Your Candidate Into the White House, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Untitled project notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Practice Pop-Up Card Sets prototypes, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer planning notes (folder 1 of 3), undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer planning notes (folder 2 of 3), undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer planning notes (folder 3 of 3), undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer promotional prototypes, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer 'Ideas' process plans, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Pocket Paper Engineer 'Ideas', undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Instructions for Assembly patents, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Treehouse, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - A Guide to the History of Movable & Pop-up Books prototype, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Promotional poster, undated (Box OV 1, Folder 1a)
  - Personal statements and questions, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Untitled pop-up prototypes (folder 1 of 8), undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Untitled pop-up prototypes (folder 2 of 8), undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Untitled pop-up prototypes (folder 3 of 8), undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Untitled pop-up prototypes (folder 4 of 8), undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Untitled pop-up prototypes (folder 5 of 8), undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Untitled pop-up prototypes (folder 6 of 8), undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Untitled pop-up prototypes (folder 7 of 8), undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Untitled pop-up prototypes (folder 8 of 8), undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Series 3: Ephemera and Personal Papers, 1979-2013